Guide to the Evsey D. Domar Papers, 1939-1995 and undated (bulk 1957-1989)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Research Materials, 1944-1995 and undated (Box 8)
  - Effect of the Interest Rate (2 of 2) (Box 11)
  - Problem of Empire's Models (3 folders) (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - On the Probability of Russian Serfdom: (Box 11)
    - Working Paper, 1982 (Box 11)
    - Earlier Drafts (Box 11)
    - Notes, and Mathematical Models (Box 11)
    - Correspondence (Box 11)
    - Correspondence and Draft Paper (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous Notes and Papers (Box 11)
  - Research Statistics Results: (4 folders) (Box 11)
    - Serf and Land Prices (Box 11)
    - Classes and Distribution (Box 11)
    - Land Total and Per Soul (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - Various Federal Reserve board papers by Domar, 1944-1946 (Box 12)
  - Value-Added Tax -- Derivations (Box 12)
  - Value-Added Tax -- Research Papers (1 of 2) (Box 12)
  - Value-Added Tax -- Research Papers (2 of 2) (Box 12)
  - Value-Added Tax -- Derivations (Box 12)
  - Tax Timing Derivation (Box 12)
  - "On the Pyramiding of the Value-Added Tax" (Box 12)
  - Value-Added Tax (Box 12)
  - "The Economics of Soviet Foreign Trade Policy," 1958 (Box 12)
  - Expansion and Employment, 1947 (Box 12)
  - "Does the Timing of the Tax Payment Matter?": Correspondence, Manuscript, and Research Papers, 1994 (Box 12)
  - "If I Were George Washington: A Suggested Dissertation Topic" (Box 12)
  - "Jewish History in One Lesson" (Box 12)
  - Book Reviews of Journals (5 folders) (Box 12)
  - Index Project (Box 12)
  - Bibliography: Russian-English (Box 12)
  - "The Rise of Lithuania" (Box 12)
  - II-C through II-D (Box 12)
  - Beginning (Box 12)
  - Not Used (Box 12)
  - World Country Bibliography (Box 12)
  - "Bibliography on Serfdom" (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous Serf (Box 12)
  - World Country Bibliography (Box 12)
  - The Future of Serfs (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous Lectures on the Soviet Economy, 1989-1992 (Box 13)
  - Value-Added Tax Calculations (Box 13)
  - The Blind Men and the Elephant: An Essay on Isms, 1988 (Box 13)
  - Writings By Others (3 folders) (Box 13)
  - Home and Office Books (Box 13)
  - "Reflections on Perestroika," 1995 (Box 13)
  - "On Deficits and Debts" (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Serfdom (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Slavery (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Subject Headings (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Notecards (Box 13)
  - Serfdom Notes (1 of 2) (Box 13)
  - Serfdom Notes (2 of 2) (Box 13)
  - Russian History Notecards (Box 13)
  - Mailing List - untitled (Box 13)
  - "Elephant Mailings" Cards (Box 13)
  - Slavery/Serfdom Note Cards (Box 13)
  - Slavery/Serfdom Note Cards (Box 13)
  - Comparative Studies Note Cards (Box 13)
  - "Empire" Bibliography (Box 13)
  - "Empire" Note Cards (Box 13)
  - Untitled Note Cards (Box 13)
- Printed Materials, 1904-1989 and undated(bulk 1957-1989) (Box 13)
  Mostly hardcover books from Domar's personal library. Some relate to his research interests while others are editions or translations of his own published works. Includes microfilm of 1904 Russian work on unknown subject matter, and 1980 translation of 1861 Russian work on serfdom in Russia.
  - Eseje o teorii ekonomickeho rastu, 1966 (Essays in the Theory of Economic Growth, 1957) (two copies) (Box 14)
  - Essays in the Theory of Economic Growth, 1957 (Box 14)
  - History of Political Economy, 1978 (Box 14)
  - Capitalism, socialism, and serfdom, 1989 (Box 14)
  - Szkice z teorii wzrostu gospodarczego, 1957 (Essays in the Theory of Economic Growth, 1957) (two copies) (Box 14)
  - Essays in the Theory of Economic Growth, 1957 (Japanese edition, 1959) (two copies) (Box 14)
  - Profitti imposta e investimenti (Essays in the Theory of Economic Growth, 1957) (Box 14)
  - The Determinants of Russian State Income, 1800-1914: An Economic Analysis, Volume 1, L. Dwight Israelsen, 1979 (Box 14)
  - The Serf Population in Russia, A. Troynitskiy, 1861 (Translated in 1980) (Box 14)
  - The Fall and Rise of the American Academic Establishment: The Revolution of 1960-2020 [ 1971?] (three copies) [Domar?] (Box 14)
  - The Comparative Performance of Social and Private Organizations: The Case of Postwar Yugoslav Agriculture, M. L. Boyd, 1984 (Box 14)
  - Microfilm (reel): "Microfilm of Duvtpueb's [sp?] Book, 1904" (Russian work) (Box 14)
- Course Materials, 1939-1985 and undated (Box 14)
  Lecture notes and texts, reading lists, workshop materials, exam questions, and other materials related to Domar's teaching career.
  - Wellsley College Teaching (Box 15)
  - Comparative Economic Systems: (Box 15)
    - Reading Lists, 1982-1983 (1 of 6) (Box 15)
    - Reading Lists, 1956-1982 (2 of 6) (Box 15)
    - Reading Lists and Student Bibliographies (3 of 6) (Box 15)
    - The Cost of the Great Depression (4 of 6) (Box 15)
    - Government Percentages (5 of 6) (Box 15)
    - Questionnaire (6 of 6) (Box 15)
  - Capitalizing Socialism and Growth: (Box 15)
    - Reading List (1 of 9) (Box 15)
    - Reading List (2 of 9) (Box 15)
    - Socialism (3 of 9) (Box 15)
    - Capitalism (4 of 9) (Box 15)
    - Growth (5 of 9) (Box 15)
    - Growth (6 of 9) (Box 15)
    - Reading List (7 of 9) (Box 15)
    - Examinations (8 of 9) (Box 15)
    - Examinations (9 of 9) (Box 15)
  - "A Note on Interindustry Wage Differentials in Yugoslavia and the US" by Clifford Donn (Box 15)
  - Workshop in Comparative Economic Systems (Box 15)
  - Macroeconomics Reading List, 1970-1971 (Box 15)
  - National Income Problem (Box 15)
  - Macroeconomics Reference Tables (Box 15)
  - Macroeconomics Lecture Notes, Exam, and Paper: "Stability Without Planning: The American Expansion" (Box 15)
  - Computation of Gross National Product and Its Components (Box 15)
  - Macroeconomics Interest Rate Lecture Notes (Box 15)
  - Macroeconomics Annual Cost of Capital (Box 15)
  - The Definition of Money and the Money Illusion of Real Balance Effects (Box 15)
  - Macroeconomics Price Flexibility and Employment Lecture Notes (Box 15)
  - "Fiscal and Monetary Policy: The Burden of the Federal Debt" (Box 15)
  - Elementary Economics Lecture Notes (Box 15)
  - Macroeconomics Old Reading List (Box 15)
  - Elementary Economics Exams (Box 15)
  - Economics of the Soviet Union and China: Reading Lists, 1964-1978 (Box 16)
  - Economics of the Soviet Union and China: Reading Lists, 1985 and 1979 (Box 16)
  - Ditto Materials (Box 16)
  - Problems of Russian Economic History: (Box 16)
    - Reading List, 1981-1984 (1 of 8) (Box 16)
    - Reading List, 1972-1980 (2 of 8) (Box 16)
    - From Peter I to 1861: Notes and Papers (3 of 8) (Box 16)
    - From Peter I to 1861: Notes and Papers (4 of 8) (Box 16)
    - From Emancipation to Revolution: 1861-1917: Notes (5 of 8) (Box 16)
    - Kievan and Appanage Periods: Parts I-II: Lecture Notes and Papers (6 of 8) (Box 16)
    - Development of Serfdom: 16th and 17th Centuries: Part III: Lecture Notes and Papers (7 of 8) (Box 16)
    - Article Reprints (8 of 8) (Box 16)
  - Soviet Agriculture (Box 16)
  - Soviet Planning: Investment Dervisions (Box 16)
  - Russian Economics: Reading List (Box 16)
  - Topics of Economic History: (Box 16)
    - Reading List, 1980-1982 (Box 16)
    - Reading List, 1980-1983 (Box 16)
    - Money (Box 16)
    - Agrarian Relations and Enclosures: Notes and Papers (Box 16)
    - Slavery and Serfdom: Papers and Graphs (Box 16)
    - Notes (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 16)
  - Black Death, 1981 (Box 16)
  - Ph.D. Examinations: (Box 16)
    - Macroeconomics (Box 16)
    - Microeconomics (Box 16)
    - Economic Developments (Box 16)
    - Fiscal Economics (Box 16)
    - John Hopkins University (Box 16)
    - Economic History (Box 16)
    - Comparative Economic Systems, Socialism, and Economic Development (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 16)
  - Macroeconomics: Final Exam (Box 16)
  - Problems in Russian Economic History: Examinations (Box 16)
  - Examination: Public Finance and Fiscal Policy (Box 16)
  - Final Exam: John Hopkins, Stanford, and University of Michigan (Box 16)
  - Final Examination: Business Cycles (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous Examinations (Box 16)
  - UCLA Teaching (Box 16)
  - Stockholm Teaching (Box 16)
  - Student Evaluations (1 of 2) (Box 16)
  - Student Evaluations (2 of 2) (Box 16)
  - Consumer Markets: Fact Sheets (Box 16)
  - Undergraduate Macroeconomics (Box 16)
  - Macroeconomics: (Box 17)
    - The Balanced Budget Multiplies (Box 17)
    - Aggregate Algebraic Problems (Box 17)
    - Questionnaire on the Theory of National Income and Employment (Box 17)
    - Theory of National Income and Employment (Box 17)
    - Keynesian and Classical Models (Box 17)
    - Consumption Function (Box 17)
    - National Budgets (Box 17)
    - Investment Decisions (Box 17)
    - Input-Output Tables (1 of 2) (Box 17)
    - Input-Output Tables (2 of 2) (Box 17)
    - Business Cycles (Box 17)
    - National Budget Table, 1953-1955 (Box 17)
    - Uses of Net Corporate Income, 1950-1959 (Box 17)
    - Difference Equations (Box 17)
  - Data on Income and Savings (Box 17)
  - Topics in Economic History (Box 17)
  - Course Notes (Box 17)
  - Elementary Relationships in Microeconomics (Box 17)
  - Economic Growth and Development (Box 17)
  - Fiscal and Monetary Policy (Box 17)
  - Distribution of Tax Payments Table (Box 17)
  - "On the Optimal Compensation of a Socialist Managee" (Box 17)
  - "On the Optimal Compensation of a Socialist Manager" (Box 17)
  - "On the Optimal Compensation of a Socialist Manager" (Box 17)
  - "The Effect of a Proportional Subsidy on a Tax on the Quality and Quantity of Output" (1 of 2) (Box 17)
  - "The Effect of a Proportional Subsidy on a Tax on the Quality and Quantity of Output" (2 of 2) (Box 17)
  - "Poor Old Capitalism" (Box 17)
  - Planning and Market Relations: IEA Meeting, 1970 (1 of 2) (Box 17)
  - Planning and Market Relations: IEA Meeting, 1970 (2 of 2) (Box 17)
  - "Stability Without Planning?" (1 of 2) (Box 17)
  - "Stability Without Planning?" (2 of 2) (Box 17)
  - Stencils for Courses (Box 17)
  - Topics in Economic History: Examinations (Box 17)
  - Macroeconomics: (Box 17)
    - Examination (1 of 3) (Box 17)
    - Final Exams (2 of 3) (Box 17)
    - Student Evaluations (3 of 3) (Box 17)
  - Harvard Teaching (Box 17)
  - Latrobe University (Australia) Teaching (Box 17)
  - Russian Economic History: (Box 17)
    - Reading List, 1984 (Box 17)
    - Reading List, 1985 (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 17)
  - Domar's Course Notebook: (Box 18)
    - Mathematical Theory of Probability: 1939-1940 (Box 18)
    - Calculus of Finite Differences, 1939-1940 (Box 18)
    - Statistics, 1939-1940 (Box 18)
    - Advanced Calculus Theory (Box 18)
    - Introduction to the Theory of Point Sets, 1939-1940 (Box 18)
    - Math 114a (Box 18)
  - Essays in Economics of Expansion (Box 18)
  - Bibliographies (Box 18)
  - Curriculum Vitae of Evsey Domar, 1973 and 1985 (Box 18)
  - Biographical: Jews in Harbin Interview with Domar (Box 18)
  - Mexico Travel (1 of 2) (Box 18)
  - Mexico Travel (2 of 2) (Box 18)
  - Biographical: The Story of My Thesis (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous Travel (Box 18)
  - Various Research and Thesis Topics (Box 18)
  - USSR Travel (Box 18)
  - Soviet Union Trip (Box 18)
  - Trip to USSR, 1971 (1 of 2) (Box 18)
  - Trip to USSR, 1971 (2 of 2) (Box 18)
  - Boris Khazanov Resume, 1973 (Box 18)
  - Humorous Speech Given for Retirement of Barbara Kligelnhagen (Box 18)
  - Article Reference to Domar (Box 18)
  - Photographs (Portraits of Domar) (3 items) (Box 18)
- Oversize Material (Box 18)
  - Research Materials and Writings (Opaperfolder Folder 1, Box 18)